SURAJ BOLANAVAR

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I am a Software Engineer with 3+ years of professional experience in web development. I am skilled in using MERN stack technologies to design and develop quality products. My objective is to be the best web developer I can be and contribute to the tech industry with all that I know I can do.

SKILLS

React Js 8/10 Javascript 7/10 Node Js 7/10 Express Js 8/10 CSS3 8/10 HTML5 9/10 Mongo DB 6/10 Docker 6/10 Kubernetes 4/10

EXPERIENCE

Project: IVP Operations Hub [Aug 2017 - Present]

Position: Software Engineer

Company: 1. L&T Technology Services [Aug 2017 - Mar 2019] 2. Synamedia pvt ltd. [Aug 2019 - Present]

Management portal to provision, operate & monitor the Infinite Video

Platform services

Roles and Responsibilities

- **Developer** cum **Scrum Master** and carried out Scrum activities -Product backlog, Sprint planning, Sprint daily, retrospect etc.
- Design and development of micro services and UI components following **DevOps** practices.
- Mentoring Juniors, Code reviews, active re-factoring. Production support, debugging and bug fixing.
- Working with version control systems like **git**, **gitHub** etc.
- Developing and implementing highly-responsive user interface components using React, material ui.

Recognition and Opportunities

- Star performer of the month award
- Key performer of the sprint [Twice]
- Visited Israel to collaborate and develop Web application to showcase in IBC(International Broadcasting Convention)

CONTACT



svbsuraj@gmail.com



Linked In

EDUCATION



Bachelor of Engineering

College: Sri Siddhartha Institute of Technology Tumkur

Branch: Computer Science

CGPA: 8.67 (79.2%)